Guide to the Sally Belfrage Papers TAM.189
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sally Belfrage Papers
1903-2000
1960-1990
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Belfrage, Sally, 1936-
Pomerance, Eve
Pomerance, Moby
TAM.189
21.5 Linear Feet in 44 boxes and 3 oversize folders in shared boxes.
Sally Mary Caroline Belfrage (1936-1994) was an independent leftist, world-traveling journalist, and writer born in Hollywood, California. She was the daughter of Cedric Belfrage and Molly Castle, two radical British writers. Her books include: A Room in Moscow; Un-American Activities: A Memoir of the Fifties; and Freedom Summer. The collection includes Belfrage's correspondence, manuscripts and documentation of her creative and political activities.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of the following materials which are restricted until 2021:
Series I. Biographical, subseries A-C: boxes 1-3.
Series II. Correspondence (All): boxes 9-23, and box 40.
Series III. Writings (first box): box 23.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Eve and Moby Pomerance in 1997; additional materials were found in the repository in 2014. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1997.002, 1997.003, and 2014.133.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged into seven series, three of which have been organized into sub-series. Folders are arranged alphabetically or chronologically within each series.
Series I: Biographical Materials, 1903-1994
Subseries I:A: General, 1992-1994
Subseries I:B: Biographical, 1903-1990
Subseries I:C Diaries, 1947-1985
Subseries I:D: Notebooks, 1957-1993
Subseries I:E: Appointment and Address Books, 1939-1990
Series II: Correspondence, 1934-2000
Subseries II:A: Family Correspondence, 1934-1994
Subseries II:B: Correspondence -- Alphabetical, 1950-1994
Subseries II:C: Correspondence -- Chronological, 1947-2000
Series III: Writings, 1845-2000
Subseries III:A: Articles, Reviews, Fiction, 1959-1999
Subseries III:B: Room in Moscow, 1845-1992
Subseries III:C: Freedom Summer, 1952-1993
Subseries III:D: Flowers of Emptiness, 1933-1985
Subseries III:E: The Crack, 1980-1991
Subseries III:F: Transcript Folders, 1980-1990
Subseries III:G: Un-American Activities, 1983-2000
Subseries III:H: Writings by Others, 1939-2000
Series IV: Political Activities, 1963-1984
Series V: Government Files, 1978-1995
Series VI: Photographs and Audiovisual Material, 1910s-1994
Series VII: Restricted Items
Historical/Biographical Note
Sally Mary Caroline Belfrage, independent leftist, world traveling journalist, and author of five books, was born in Hollywood, California on October 4, 1936. The daughter of Cedric Belfrage and Molly Castle, two radical British writers, she moved with her family in 1942 to the New York city area where they stayed until 1955. She went to Bronx Science High School, and briefly attended Hunter College. During their time in New York, Cedric started the independent weekly radical newspaper The National Guardian, Cedric and Molly were divorced, Cedric was arrested, and by 1955 both were deported under the provisions of the McCarran Act. Although an American citizen, Sally left with them. In London, she attended the London School of Economics and worked in publishing. In 1957, she attended the World Youth Festival in Moscow, where she then worked (editing English translations of Tolstoy) and lived for the better part of a year. During her stay she took part in a six-week tour of China, and appeared in a Russian movie, "Memories of the Heart."
Upon returning to London, she wrote her first book, A Room in Moscow (1958). While on a 1959 U.S. publicity tour, she befriended folksinger Millard Lampell, who encouraged her to visit Israel. Thus began another year of travels throughout the Near East, during which she worked on a kibbutz, met King Hussein of Jordan, and in 1960 married Sari Nashashibi, a Palestinian, so he could obtain a U.S. visa. Upon her return from the Near East; she spent the next two years traveling all over Europe (with Benjamin Sonnenberg, founder of the magazine Grand Street) before moving to New York in mid-1962.
In 1963 Belfrage traveled to Georgia and North Carolina to research the civil rights movement, and was inspired to participate in the SNCC-sponsored Freedom Summer organizing drive of 1964. She was assigned to Greenwood, Mississippi where she helped start a literacy school and a community library, participated in a voter registration drive, spent several days in jail, and went to the 1964 Democratic National Convention with the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party delegation. Her memoir Freedom Summer was published in 1965.
In November of 1965 Belfrage married playwright Bernard Pomerance (author of The Elephant Man). In 1967 her daughter Eve was born, followed in 1969 by her son Moby. After the latter's birth, the four began renting the flat at 51 Randolph Avenue in London that was to remain Sally's home until her death. In 1970, she helped found a community-based "Women's Liberation Group" which remained in operation for more than twenty years. In 1980 she published Flowers of Emptiness, about her 1976 experiences during two-month visit to a guru's ashram in India. In 1975, Sally and Bernard Pomerance separated and he moved to the United States.
In 1983-1984 Belfrage was involved in the Greenham Common Women's Nuclear Disarmament movement, and helped edit its broadsheet "The Greenham Factor." Also in 1984, she began to visit Belfast, Northern Ireland, to research the effects of the longstanding civil conflict on Catholic and Protestant women. The resulting book, The Crack: A Belfast Year was published in 1987. The remainder of Belfrage's life was spent traveling and writing her coming of age memoir, Un-American Activities, published in 1994. She died of cancer in London in March 1994.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cedric Belfrage Papers (TAM 143)
Victor Rabinowitz Papers (TAM 123)
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains numerous and detailed diaries, notebooks (most in shorthand, and usually project or travel oriented), and appointment/address books, covering Sally Belfrage's entire literary career, as well as memorabilia, mostly from her youth. Much of the collection consists of Belfrage's prolific correspondence, including carbons of most of her own letters. There is voluminous correspondence with Cedric Belfrage, Molly Castle, Virginia Durr, Joanne Grant, John Gunther. Jessica "Decca" Mitford, Kathy Perutz, Bernard Pomerance (closed until 2021), Benjamin Sonnenburg, and Michael "Monk" Train. Other significant and/or frequent correspondents include Alan Arkin, Judith ("Savita") Brandt, Kim Chernin, Alexander Cockburn, Frank Conroy, George Feifer, Albert Finney, Alger Hiss, Millard Lampell, Staughton Lynd, Stewart Mott, Vladimir Pozner, Zell Rabin, Muriel Rukeyser, Harrison Salisbury, Kwame Ture, Fred Wiseman, and Sol Yurick.
Manuscripts, correspondence, interviews, clippings, and other materials document the researching, writing, publication and reception of Belfrage's five books, including transcripts of some sixty interviews conducted for The Crack. There are also like materials for her shorter writings, and a set of unpublished and published writings by others, principally Judith ("Savita") Brandt. Belfrage's involvement in the Greenham Common, a 1980s feminist peace encampment in England, as well as other political and feminist activities, is documented through writings, correspondence and ephemera. This collection also contains FBI files on Sally and Cedric Belfrage and on Nathan Gregory and Helen Silvermaster (during World War II, Nathan was employed by the U.S. Board of Economic Warfare, and was later accused of being a Soviet spy), which were obtained by Sally Belfrage under the Freedom of Information Act. Finally, the collection includes approximately 1700 photographs which document Belfrage's family and travels (including Moscow, China, the Middle East, the southern United States, Mexico, Cuba and Ireland), as well as audiovisual materials from Belfrage's memorial service, the posthumous "Symphony Space" event, an audiorecording related to Freedom Summer, 2 undated interviews with "Marg Powers" and "Emma G," an audiorecording of the 1989 Conference on Civil Rights Studies, and an audiorecording of "The White Integrationalists" by Colin D. Edwards.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact [repository contact information] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact [repository contact information] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Separated Material
Approximately 160 sound recordings (almost all are audiocassettes) have been separated and added to the Library's Sound collection. A preliminary inventory is available.
Drafts (documents); Correspondence.; Journalism -- United States.; Civil rights workers |z United States.; Photographs.; Printed ephemera.; Transcripts.; Notebooks; Appointment books.; Government records; Diaries; Manuscripts for publication.; Anti-communist movements |z United States |x History.; American literature |x Women authors.; Clippings (information artifacts); Wiseman, Frederick.; Yurick, Sol, 1925-2013; Silvermaster, Nathan Gregory; Belfrage family; Greenham Common Women's Peace Camp; Cockburn, Alexander; Chernin, Kim; Castle, Molly, 1908-; Belfrage, Cedric, 1904-1990.; Brandt, Judith E.; Belfrage, Sally, 1936-; Hiss, Alger; Arkin, Alan; Carmichael, Stokely; Train, Michael; Sonnenberg, Ben; Grant, Joanne; Finney, Albert, 1936-; Feifer, George; Durr, Virginia Foster; Conroy, Frank, 1936-2005; Rabin, Zell.; Pozner, Vladimir, 1905-1992; Salisbury, Harrison E. (Harrison Evans), 1908-1993; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980; Gunther, John, 1901-1970; Lynd, Staughton; Lampbell, Millard; Mott, Stewart; Mitford, Jessica, 1917-1996; Pomerance, Bernard.; Perutz, Kathy.; Pomerance, Eve; Pomerance, Moby
- Series I: Biographical Materials, 1903-1994
  - Subseries I:A: General (Note: Closed until 2021), 1992-1994
    Conditions Governing Access
    Subseries I:A is closed until 2021.
    - Detailed Chronology of SB's Life; Program for her memorial, 1992, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries I:B: Biographical (Note: Closed until 2021), 1903-1990
    Subseries I:B is closed until 2021.
    - Notes about Sally and Nicky - Kept by Molly Castle, ca.1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - School Reports About SB, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - SB's Report Cards and Diplomas, 1943-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Crier" - Hessian Hills School Journal, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Farm and Wilderness camp, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The Lightning Bug" - Farm and Wilderness Camp Newsletter; c. 1940's, late, ca.1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Finney Farm Follies" - Newsletter produced by SB and Friends, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wallace, Henry A- Signature on Pamphlet, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Croton-Harmon Yearbook, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - School Reports on Gandhi and the French Revolution; c. 1950's, early, ca.1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Memorabilia from time at 500 Kappock St. and 65th St., ca.1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - SB's Certificate of Baptism - by Claude Williams, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bronx High School of Science Yearbook, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, ca.1956-1965, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - SB in various Arabic Newspapers, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Application for a visa to Cuba (from Czech Embassy), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - SB Resume, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with High School and friends from High School, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bronx Science - Class of 1954 Alumni Directory, ca.1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Memorabilia- postcards, etc., undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Belfrage, Cedric: miscellaneous articles, 1931-1954, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Belfrage, Cedric: Obituaries, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Belfrage, Cedric: Independent Obituary and controversy ensuing, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Belfrage, Cedric: condolence letters, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Belfrage, Cedric: Memorial and misc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Castle, Molly Pigott: Misc., 1903-1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Castle, Molly Pigott: Diary, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Castle, Molly: writings, by and about, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Castle, Molly: published articles, ca.1935-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letter to 'Sister Kenna' from Henry Owen Jones, Sister Kenna's Expenses, 1907, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries I:C, Part 1: Diaries (Note: Closed until 2021), 1947-1985
    Subseries I:C part 1 is closed until 2021.
    - Diaries, 1947, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, ca.1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Diary; 5 Nov 1958- 7 Mar 1961, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Notes: mostly on Middle East, ca.1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Diary (Plus comment from 1975); 9 Mar 1961- May 1962, 1975, 1961-1962, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Diary; 5 Jun 1962- Sep 1963, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Diary; 4 Oct 1963- Jun 1964, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Diary; 2 Jul 1964- May 1968, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I:C, part 2: Diaries (Closed until 2021), 1947-1985
    Subseries I:C part 2 is closed until 2021.
    - Diary Fragments, 1969-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Diary (Some in the form of letters to the deceased John Gunther); 9 Nov 1970- 28 Apr 1973, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Photographs"-- Brief Autobiographical Sketches, ca.1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Diary (pp. 1-54); Jan 1973- Oct 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Diary (pp. 55-94); Nov 1974- July 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Diary (pp. 95-193); Aug 1975-Nov 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Diary (pp. 194-247); Nov 1975- Apr 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Diary; May 1976- 5 Apr 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Autobiographical Manuscript (?)-- In the form of (reworked) letters to the deceased John Gunther., ca.1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Diary Fragments: "Re-typing all the little notes of years;" 1979, and earlier, ca.1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Diary; Aug 6 1981-Jan 10 1983, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Diary CLOSED UNTIL 2021; Oct 18 1982 - Jul 13 1984, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - SB's loose notes/ diaries/ letters (from her) CLOSED UNTIL 2021; c 1957-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Subseries I:D: Notebooks, 1957-1993
    - Notebooks: Moscow and China, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Reading Notebook, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - General Middle East Notebook, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Diary/Notebook From Travels in Middle East, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Notebooks: 1963-1964 Diary; 1964-1965 Diary/General; 1960's General; "1970+" General; 1968-1972 General, ca.1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Large Diary Notebooks (in shorthand); Nov 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Notebooks: 1973 "Sperlonga" (etc.); 1975 Amsterdam/Caparica; 1977 "SES & Joep Diary", 1977 "Kenya & Malaria Diary"; 1977-1978 General, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Diary Notebook (in shorthand); Jan 1977-Nov 1981, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Diary Notebooks from Reunion Trip to China, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Notebooks: 1982 General; 1984 "Bill Mason"; 2 undated 1980's, 1980-1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Diary Notebooks (in shorthand); Jan 1982-Jul 1984; Mar 1985- Nov 1987, 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - General Notebooks: 1985; 1986-1987; 1988, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks: 1990 Poland; 1991 Israel (etc); 1992-1993 General, with Un-American Activities notes; 2 General undated (1990s), 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs from Notebooks, 1973-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3A)
  - Subseries I:E: Appointment and Address Books., 1939-1990
    - Xeroxed Address book; [1980s], ca.1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Notebooks, from travels in 1990s; [1990s], ca.1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Address and appointment books, 1955-1970 (Box 7, Folder data_value_missing_d037e932097677ae17e32c86838721ed)
    - Address and appointment books (some in envelopes by year); loose address book notes etc., 1971-1993 (Box 8, Folder data_value_missing_02f80feaee497d40f4ed20a2614db960)
    - Last Appointment/ Address book, 1994 (Box 8, Folder data_value_missing_5c8a637686181ce13bf93d60a34f9d78)
    - Passports, 1939-1956, 1960 (Box 8, Folder data_value_missing_2f0408131b2f1f8fbd8e250c1d2d7e9f)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1934-2000
  Access to Series II is restricted until 2021.
  - Subseries II:A: Family Correspondence (Note: Closed until 2021), 1934-1994
    - Belfrage-Hertz, (Zribi), Anne (SB's Sister), 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Belfrage-Hertz, (Zribi), Anne (SB's Sister), 1972-1992 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, to Molly Castle, 1934-1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Belfrage, Cedric (with SB), 1945-1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Belfrage, Cedric, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Belfrage, Mary, (nee Bernick) (SB's stepmother), 1958-1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Belfrage, Nick, 1954-1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Belfrage, Nick, 1965-1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Belfrage, Sydney H.: Correspondence regarding Cedric Belfrage's father, who was a physician to Virginia Woolf, 1982, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Castle, Molly: Childhood letters from Nick and Sally Belfrage, ca.1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Castle, Molly (with SB), 1954-1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Castle, Molly, 1963-1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Castle, Molly, 1968-1981 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Castle, Molly, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Castle, Molly (Letters from Nick Belfrage), undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Hertz, Anne-Marie (SB's Stepmother), 1961-1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Martin, Josephine "Jo" (SB's Stepmother), 1958-1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Pomerance, Bernard {CLOSED until 2021}, 1965-1969 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Pomerance, Bernard {CLOSED until 2021}, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Pomerance, Bernard {CLOSED until 2021}, 1980-1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Pomerance, Bernard (separation and divorce) {CLOSED until 2021}, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Pomerance, Bernard (misc. Programs for plays, selected reviews), 1968-1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pomerance, Harriet and Leon, 1966-1976 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Pomerance, Leon, 1977-1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Relatives: Other, 1948-1978 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries II:B: Correspondence -- Alphabetical (Note: Closed until 2021), 1950-1994
    - Agel, Jerome B., 1979-1991 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Alf, Herbert, 1960-1991 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Aloni, Nissim, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Arkin, Alan, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Asher, Aaron (Viking Press), 1964-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Aukin, Liane, 1987-1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Baker, Brock (Re: John Gunther), 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Basheer, Tahseen, 1960-1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Bauer, Ed, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Berger, Fran (nee Tesca), 1984-1993 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Bernstein, Walter, 1978-1986 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Bijl, Jacob ("Joep"); Mar-Jul 1977 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Bijl, Jacob; Aug 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Bijl, Jacob, 1979-1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Bloch, Don, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Baden Family, 1973-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Braidoff, Daniel, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Brandt, Heidi, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Brandt, Judith ("Savita"), 1972-1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Brooke, Dinah ("Pankaja"), 1972-1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Brown, Joe David (Correspondence and Story About), ca.1958-1980 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Buckman, Peter, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Canfield, Cass, ca.1956 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Chernan, Kim (a.k.a. Elain Kusnitz) [spelling??], 1958, 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Chesterman, Jim, 1952-1956 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Cina, Carol, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Clemmey, Mary, 1974-1994 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Cockburn, Alexander, 1984-1988 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Cook, Lindsey, 1988-1994 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Condron, Andy, 1958-1966, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Conroy, Frank (Including a manuscript), ca.1962-1985 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Corden, Richard, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Deem, George, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - De Jong, Carole, 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Deutsch, Andre (Publishers), 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Diaz, Charles, 1969-1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Donovan, Rev. Vince, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Dorwick, Stephanie, 1982-1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Durr, Virginia, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Durr, Virginia, 1968-1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Emmett, Alexandra (later A. Allan, and subsequently Mrs. Arthur Schlesinger, Jr.), ca.1963-1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Fact magazine, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Farm and Wilderness Camp, ca.1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Feifer, George, 1964-1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Fennell, Desmond, 1959-1988 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Finney, Albert, ca.1960-1970, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Flapan, Simha, 1960-1963 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Furman, Laura, 1972-1980 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "Geof", 1991-1994 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Gluck, Karl, 1964-1965, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Golan, Ran, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Golden, Geoff, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Gordon, Denise, 1974-1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Grant, Joanne ("J"), 1958-1977 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Grant, Joanne, 1978-1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Grant, Joanne, 1984-1994 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Grant, Joanne CLOSED UNTIL 2021, 1984-1991 (Box 14, Folder 2A)
    - Granta, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Griffin, Susan, 1984-1990 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Grosso, Horacio, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Grunwald, Harry, 1982-1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Gunther, John ("JG") (photocopies; location of originals unknown), 1963-1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Gunther, John (originals); Jun-End, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Gunther, John (originals), 1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Gunther, John (originals); Jan- Mar, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Gunther, John (Manuscripts), 1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Gunther, John (Will, Obituaries), 1970 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Hacker, Marilyn, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Haynes, Jim, 1975-1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)